# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hello everyone, I am Wang Gang
# 今天跟大家分享一个水井
Today I am going to share this well with you guys
# 这个水井是我伯爷20年前打的
It was dug by my uncle 20 years ago
# 很深很深
It is very deep
# 下面掏了大概6米深
Its depth is about 6 metres
# 这个水井用的时候就揭开盖子往上面提水
you need to open the lid and lift the water from inside
# 现在我伯爷伯娘他们年纪大了
Now that my uncle and aunt are getting aged
# 他们提水没那么方便
It is not very convenient for them to lift water
# 然后就这个安全特别有隐患
Also, there is a safety risk
# 因为我小时候就掉到过这种水井里面
as I did fall into such a well when I was a child
# 还好不是很深
It was lucky that the well was not very deep
# 然后我今天在店里面买了那个压水器
Today I bought a water pump from the store
# 等一下把它坐在这个盖子上面
I am going to install it on the lid
# 直接压水压起来就可以用了
let it pump up the water for our use
# 特别的方便
which is much more convenient
# 这个就是压水器
This is the water pump
# 这样子挤压
you press the lever like this
# 那现在我们要把这个脚装上去
So now we need to nail its 'legs'
# 这个装好以后就不用提水了
You no longer need to lift water once you have got this
# 要得呀 就拿这个来压
That's lovely. I will use this
# 你去哪里耍去了
Where have you been?
# 去你姑婆哪里耍去了
Your grandaunt's
# 哦
Oh
# 来帮着把这个水井整一下
Could you give me a hand fixing this well?
# 我买了一个（压水器）回来
I bought back a water pump
# 前面弄反了 我怎么说钻起火花了
I was doing the reverse. No wonder there were sparkles.
# 刚刚好
It is just fitting
# 大功告成
Works done!
# 现在我们把这个丢下去试一下
Now let's drop in the hose and have a try
# 这里弄好之后到时候再把边上用爆炸螺丝固定一下
After finishing this I am gonna nail the lid to the brim
# 尝试一下
let's try
# 居然失败了
It fails, why?
# 他居然爆出来了
This little stuff, it jumps out - surprising
# 加一点水撒
What about putting in some water
# 我还是说加一点水
This is just what I am thinking about
# 现在加一点水试一下
let's add some water and have another try
# 好像有点效果了
It seems to work
# 为什么这个管子要扁呢
Why this pipe is being pressed flat
# 这个我感觉挺慢的
I find it not efficient enough
# 肯定是我们这个管子买错了
It must be that we have a wrong type of hose
# 因为这个管子是软的
this one is pretty elastic
# 可能要硬的
probably a hard one is needed
# 因为这个一吸它就就扁了
because it flattens once you try to draw the water
# 只要能接上就可以了
It will do as long as it can be joined to the pump
# 现在我们要换一下这个管子
Now we need to replace the pipe
# 因为这个一抽就扁了
because this one will be pressed flat if you pump the water
# 现在准备把这个换一下
I am preparing to replace it
# 帮我弄一下
Could you lend me a hand?
# 这里都差不多了
It is almost done here
# 留长了一会儿又要扁
It still flattens if you leave this too long
# 这样子撒
like this?
# 嗯
yeah
# 你看见证奇迹的时刻
It is the time for miracles!
# 一下子就来了
The water comes out immediately
# 这个水（水龙头）比较短
The tap is a bit too short
# 到这里就流下来了不太方便
The water drops down nearby, which is quite inconvenient
# 最好就是到这个位置
I hope it to flow to this length
# 这个位置软管不太适合
An elastic pipe is not suitable for this purpose
# 然后砍一根我们家的竹子应该没问题
A bamboo pipe would be very nice
# 要得 试一下
It's done. Have a try
# 可以了伯娘
It works, auntie
# 可以撒
perfect
# 你看一下伯娘
Have a look, auntie
# 可以撒
It is working
# 让我来压一下
Let me try
# 你来压下嘛
Come on
# 要快一点
You need to do it faster
# 没得事得
It's fine
# 好了本期视频就到这里吧
Okay, this is all for today's video
# 又跟伯爷伯娘省了很多力气
have spared them some efforts
# 因为他们弯腰提水确实不容易
because, you see, it is really difficult for them to bend down to lift water
# 深有体会
I genuinely relate to that
# 好收拾一下 完事儿了
Let's tidy up a bit since the work is finished